Location Brooklyn, New York
Website https://sites.google.com/view/scottspitze
Github https://github.com/spspitze
Email spspitze@gmail.com
Cell (618)698-3012
Citizenship USA, Australia

Summary

I'm a labor economist interested in improving worker wages, mobility, and productivity. I'm especially interested in worker education (both degree and non-degree), worker skills, worker occupation choice, and firm needs. Experienced in asking and answering research questions, cleaning and analyzing data, leading and mentoring research teams, and communicating with and helping clients. I'm an expert in R and the tidyverse, including using these tools to interact with SQL databases.

Experience

The Burning Glass Institute

Senior Economist Economist June 2023 - Present March 2022 - May 2023

I mainly work on client based projects studying how to improve outcomes for workers, either though education, skills, or occupation selection. Notable projects include

- 1. Using North Carolina administrative data to estimate the ROI for each program in the UNC system.
- 2. Using job profiles and vacancy postings data to study career outcomes for Texas public university and college students and the demand for students by school and major.
- Using job profiles to track worker attainment of non-degree credentials (used NLP techniques to standardize raw credential data). Analyzing how credentials affect worker outcomes to rank credentials and credential providers.

I take client questions and translate them into actionable analysis.

Created an R package to streamline interaction with the company Snowflake server.

Education

Ph.D. Economics, University of Georgia, 2022

M.A. Economics (Doctoral Track), University of Iowa, 2018.

B.A. Economics, Summa Cum Laude, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 2015.

Working Papers

"The Equilibrium Effects of Domestic Outsourcing"

"Currency Competition with Uncertain Acceptance: The Case of Cryptocurrencies" with Fan Liang

Honors & Awards

St. Louis Fed Ph.D. Internship 2021

Bonbright Graduate Assistant 2020-2021

Graduate College Summer Fellowship, University of Iowa 2017

Conference Presentations

2022 Society of Labor Economics, Minneapolis

2021 St. Louis Fed Ph.D. Interns Workshop

North American Summer Meetings of the Econometric Society, Montréal

2020 90th Annual Meeting of the Southern Economic Association, New Orleans I-85 Macroeconomics Workshop, Atlanta Fed

2019 Mini Conference on Search and Money, Wisconsin School of Business, Madison Midwest Macroeconomics Meetings, University of Georgia, Athens

Teaching

Principles of Macroeconomics, University of Georgia, Fall 2019

Principles of Macroeconomics, University of Iowa, Spring 2018

Miscellaneous

Programming Languages: Python, R, Stata

References

Gad Levanon

Chief Economist Burning Glass Institute Email glevanon@burningglassinstitute.org

Roozbeh Hosseini

Professor of Economics University of Georgia Email roozbeh@uga.edu Martin Gervais

Professor of Economics University of Georgia Email martin.gervais@uga.edu